export default Dpe2 = [
    {
        question: "1. Which of the following is the formula of bleaching powder ?",
        options: ["CaOCl2",
            "CaCl2",
            "Ca(OH)2",
            "CaOCl3"],
        correct_option: "CaOCl2"
    },
    {
        question: "2. Magnesium hydroxide is otherwise called as",
        options: ["Milk of magnesia",
            "Brine solution",
            "A strong acid",
            "None"],
        correct_option: "Milk of magnesia"
    },
    {
        question: "3. Select a pair of basic salts among the following",
        options: ["Sodium chloride and sodium acetate",
            "Sodium acetate and sodium bicarbonate",
            "Sodium carbonate and sodium sulphate",
            "Sodium nitrate and sodium oxalate"],
        correct_option: "Sodium acetate and sodium bicarbonate"
    },
    {
        question: "4. Which of the following is correct?",
        options: ["Only synthetic indicators are used to identify the nature of solution",
            "Indicators are strong acids or strong bases",
            "Indicators are weak acids or weak bases",
            "Universal indicator gives the same colour at different pH values"],
        correct_option: "Only synthetic indicators are used to identify the nature of solution"
    },
    {
        question: "5. Non-metallic oxides are ____ in nature.",
        options: ["Acidic",
            "Alkaline",
            "Neutral",
            "They do not respond"],
        correct_option: "Acidic"
    },

    {
        question: "6. NaHCO3+HCl-------->; NaCl+H2+X.The gas 'X' is passed through aqueous Na2CO3 solution to form compound 'Y'.then 'X' and 'Y' are",
        options: ["X = CO2 , Y = Na2CO3",
            "X = CO2 , Y = NaHCO3",
            "X = H2 , Y = NaHCO3",
            "X = Cl2 , Y = NaOH"],
        correct_option: "X = CO2 , Y = NaHCO3"
    },
    {
        question: "7. What are the respective colours of water, lemon juice and a mixture of water & lemon juice with the pH indicator ?",
        options: ["Green, red and red",
            "Blue, red and green",
            "Orange, green and green",
            "Red, red and green"],
        correct_option: "Green, red and red"
    },

    {
        question: "The difference of the molecules of water in Gypsum and Plaster of paris is",
        options: ["3/2",
            "1/2",
            "2",
            "5/2"],
        correct_option: "3/2"
    },
    {
        question: "9. Which of the following is produced by the action of chlorine on dry slaked lime?",
        options: ["Washing soda",
            "Bleaching powder",
            "Plaster of Paris",
            "Baking soda"],
        correct_option: "Bleaching powder"
    },

    {
        question: "10. Because which of the absence of following ions, in the glucose and alcohol solution the bulb did not glow ?",
        options: ["OH+",
            "OH-",
            "H+",
            "H-"],
        correct_option: "H+"
    },
    {
        question: "11. Colour of methyl orange in alkali conditions",
        options: ["Orange",
            "Yellow",
            "Red",
            "Blue"],
        correct_option: "Yellow"
    },

    {
        question: "12. What colour would hydrochloric acid turn universal indicator ?",
        options: ["Orange",
            "Purple",
            "Yellow",
            "Red"],
        correct_option: "Red"
    },
    {
        question: "13. The reaction of an acid with a base to give a salt and water is known as",
        options: ["Neutralization",
            "Reduction",
            "Oxidation",
            "Crystallization"],
        correct_option: "Oxidation"
    },
    {
        question: "14. The acid which enters the body by the sting of bee is",
        options: ["Acetic acid",
            "Methanoic acid",
            "Sulphuric acid",
            "Tartaric acid"],
        correct_option: "Methanoic acid"
    },

    {
        question: "15. Which of the following is slightly soluble in water?",
        options: ["CaOH2 ",
            "KOH",
            "MgOH2",
            "BeOH2"],
        correct_option: "BeOH2"
    },
    {
        question: "16. Pick out the acid-base indicator",
        options: ["Methyl orange",
            "Phenaphthalein",
            "Both",
            "None"],
        correct_option: "Both"
    },
    {
        question: "17. Which of the following is not true about pH?",
        options: ["It indicates the concentration of H+ ions in solutions of less than 1 molar",
            "At pH=0,the hydronium ion concentration in 1 molar",
            "At pH=0,the hydroxyl ion concentration in 1 molar",
            "All"],
        correct_option: "All"
    },

    {
        question: "18. Which of the following is used to enhance the taste of food?",
        options: ["Sodium carbonate",
            "Sodium sulphate",
            "Sodium chloride",
            "Sodium bicarbonate"],
        correct_option: "Sodium sulphate"
    },
    {
        question: "19. The pH value of HCl decreases when addition of NaOH due to",
        options: ["Number of H+ ions increases",
            "Number of H+ ions decreases",
            "Number of OH- ions decreases",
            "None"],
        correct_option: "Number of H+ ions decreases"
    },
    {
        question: "20. Which of the following acid is injected by stinging hair of leaves of nettle plant that causing burning pain ?",
        options: ["Methanoic acid",
            "Hydrochloric acid",
            "Nitric acid",
            "Sodium thiosulphate"],
        correct_option: "Methanoic acid"
    },

    {
        question: "21. Bases turn phenolphthalein to----colour",
        options: ["Red",
            "Pink",
            "Yellow",
            "No change"],
        correct_option: "Pink"
    },
    {
        question: "22. Antacids are used",
        options: ["To produce acid in stomach",
            "To produce water in stomach",
            "To neutralize the excess base in the stomach",
            "To neutralize the excess acid in the stomach"],
        correct_option: "To neutralize the excess acid in the stomach"
    },
    {
        question: "23. Litmus solution is a dye extracted from",
        options: ["Chrysanthemum",
            "Rose",
            "Lichens",
            "None"],
        correct_option: "Lichens"
    },
    {
        question: "24. What will happen when solution of acid mixed with solution of base in a test tube ?",
        options: ["The temperature of solution increases",
            "Salt will be formed",
            "Temperature of solution remains constant",
            "The temperature of solution increases & Salt will be formed"],
        correct_option: "The temperature of solution increases & Salt will be formed"
    },
    {
        question: "25. Which of the following is the chemical formula for hydrated copper sulphate ?",
        options: ["CuSO4.6H2o",
            "CuSO4.7H2o",
            "CuSO4.2H2o",
            "CuSO4.5H2o"],
        correct_option: "CuSO4.5H2o"
    },
]